B Hunter Cornell

Data Analyst

Contact

b.hunter.cornell@gmail.com (760) 981-5127 Glen Ellyn, IL 60137

Skills

Python - SQL - C/C++ - R

Latex - Excel - Git - Unix

Statistical Analysis/Modeling

Technical Writing

Traits

Problem Solver - Analytical

Detail Oriented - Fast Learner

Determined - Efficient - Leader

Publication

Simulated Analogs of Merging
Galaxy Clusters Constrain the
Viewing Angle - Aug 2018
http://iopscience.iop.org/artic-le/10.3847/1538-4357/aacf3e/meta

Websites

linkedin.com/in/b-cornell/ github.com/B-Cornell b-cornell.github.io/

Professional Summary

Recent graduate who has published an academic paper, held a poster session at a research conference, spearheaded a multi-year data analysis/research project, and supervised more than 20 people in a professional setting

Key Words: Programming, Statistical Analysis, SQL, Python, Technical Writing, Problem Solving, Analytics

Education

B.S. Physics | University of California-Davis | June 2018

Cumulative GPA: 3.48 Physics GPA: 3.50

Experience

Data Analyst/Physics Researcher

UC Davis Physics Dept. | June 2016 - Present

- Lead data analyst and first undergraduate in our collaboration to significantly contribute to writing a published, peer-reviewed paper
- Created scripts in Python and SQL to clean and filter data into useful structures for statistical analysis
- Pushing analysis post-publication to explore new capacities and analyze different aspects

Textbook Solutions Manual Co-author

Independent Contract | June 2018 - Present

 Broke-down solutions of complex scientific problems into coherent, easy-to-understand explanations

Night & Weekend Desk Supervisor

UC Davis Library | November 2015 - June 2018

- Generated interest in library building improvement projects by researching and advocating for ideas
- Mastered multiple software packages for manipulating and maintaining library databases

HackDavis 2018

 Utilized a brand new programming language in a team to publish an applet that recursively organized data from images of text

Lab Assistant

UC Davis Physics Dept. | June 2017 - Aug 2017

 Fixed, helped develop, and improved upon two academic electronic labs by designing circuits and troubleshooting equipment